Alice Zhang

User Experience Designer with 7 years of experience in SaaS for B2B environments specializing in visual design, accessibility, and UX strategy. Specializing in transforming ambiguity into clear, usercentred solutions, with a focus on creating memorable experiences.

EXPERIENCE

UI and UX Designer - Pelesys for CAE

Richmond, Canada | January 2022-September 2024

Created high-fidelity mockups in Figma and Sketch for the redesign of two applications in a suite of web-based aviation training applications. Contributed to the in-house design system, which guided all UI design. Application designs were reviewed and implemented by a cross-functional international product team.

UX Designer - Evident Point Software for PressReader

Richmond, Canada | January 2019-November 2021

Designed new features for an interactive textbook reader and a stakeholder-requested workbook in Figma. Standardized WCAG AA-compliant branding and print design. Led competitive analysis on 14 products to inform improvements, presenting research findings to stakeholders for product development.

UX Designer & Developer - Plaid Consulting

Vancouver, Canada | May 2018-July 2019

Conducted user interviews with data analysts and research personnel from post-secondary institutions, then utilized findings to design a prototype for a data processing web application using Adobe XD and Proto.io. Application was built in ReactJS, Bootstrap and SASS, compiled with NodeJS, and tracked using Git bash.

Web Communications Assistant - DFO Canada

Vancouver, Canada | September 2015-April 2016

Converted webpages in the DFO government website to use a new template with improved accessibility by rewriting the webpages via HTML/CSS and Bootstrap. Designed the office fitness centre's monthly newsletters in Photoshop and InDesign.

EDUCATION

Simon Fraser University, Canada

BSc in Interactive Arts and Technology | 2020 Certificate in Computing Studies | 2020

Malmö University, Sweden

Interaction Design BA Course in Full-time Exchange Program | 2017

- alice-zhang-portfolio.com
- alzh13579@gmail.com
- +1 778 788 3568
- inkedin.com/in/alice-zhang
- alice_slicez
- alice_slicez

DESIGN SKILLS

Wireframing
User Interface Design
Visual Design
Print Design

UX METHODS

User Experience Research
User Interviewing
Competitor Product Analysis
User Journey Mapping
Persona Creation
Usability Testing
Accessibility Testing

TOOLS

Figma

Sketch

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator,

InDesign, Lightroom

Miro, LucidChart

Notion

Airtable

CODING

HTML

CSS/SASS

Javascript

Git Bash

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCIES

English

Mandarin Chinese